

Gonçalo Pestana

Phone: +358 44 2387316 E-mail: g6pestana@gmail.com

LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/gpestana

GitHub: https://github.com/gpestana

Website: https://gpestana.com

Gonçalo is a senior software engineer with experience in devops and backend development. His interests range from distributed systems to big data, security and web development.

He has worked in the different phases of product development from architecting to implementing and maintaining production systems. In every project he strives for achieving best development practices and high quality code while being pragmatic and having in mind every stakeholders' requirements.

Experience

NewThingsCo.Sr Software Developer 10/2017 – Present

Working as a software developer and a consultant in a IT-consultancy startup.

F-SecureSoftware Engineer 02/2016 – 10/2017

Worked as a backend software developer responsible for architecting, implementing and maintaining a production big data pipeline with highly concurrent data processing. Scaled the service from tens of MBs to GBs of data per minute, with potential for more data intake in the future. Worked on setting up and maintaining metrics, monitoring and alerting services. Developed and maintained multiple APIs and services for internal customers to access and process data. Technologies: Node.js, Python, AWS, Docker, Elasticsearch, Influxdb, NoSQL, Git, Devops, DCOS, RabbitMQ, Serveless, Microservices.

Software consultant Software Engineer 08/2013 – 02/2016

Catchbox Oy

Worked as a full-stack developer and developed a product customization engine interface with server-side integrations. Worked partially remote.

Technologies: Node.js, JavaScript, JQuery, CSS, HTML.

Eduze

Worked as a full-stack developer and developed a content cache running on constrained physical devices. The product was a success in DemoAfrica 2013. Worked partially remote. Technologies: Python, Flask, PostgreSQL, Javascript, HTML.

North Impact

Founder, full stack developer and tech advisor of early stage startups. Worked partially remote.

Technologies: Node.js, Javascript, HTML, CSS, Zapier.

Fivestars

Software engineer

co-op

03/20015 - 09/2015

Designed, and implemented a company-wide metrics and analytics pipeline. Developed the frontend used by multiple

teams.

Technologies: Python, InfluxDB, ELK stack (ElasticSearch,

Logstash, Kibana), Grafana, statsd and Angular.js.

CERN

Senior Engineer & Research intern 06/20013 – 08/2014

Worked as a software engineer and researcher for the CMS collider software team. Developed test automation for data processing in microprocessors. Published and presented

scientific paper at the ACAT2014 conference.

Technologies: Python, C, ARM processors.

Skills

Languages JavaScript, Go, Python, HTML, CSS

Frameworks Node.js, React, jQuery

Databases Elasticsearch, Influxdb, MongoDB, Redis2

Infra AWS, Docker, Jenkins, DCOS, RabbitMQ, Consul

Paradigms Microservices, Serverless, Agile, Kanban, Remote

Education

Master's of Computer Science 2017

Aalto University

Thesis title "Energy Efficiency in High Throughput Computing"

Bachelor's of Network Communication engineering 2012

Técnico Lisboa